

Dmitry Kotov

1240 Northpoint Drive San Francisco, California 94130 626.354.8430

hi@dmitrykotov.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/kotovdmitry dmitrykotov.com paradisebird.co

VIDEO PRODUCER

A crafty video producer with 7 years of filming and editing experience. A jack of all trades, being able to conceptualize and write scripts given goals or problems to solve, prepare production schedules and scout locations, props, talent, licensing, etc. Has experience shooting both outdoors and indoors, working with light set-ups, operating cameras, directing actors, and recording audio on set. Proficient user of Adobe Premiere, After Effects for editing, color correction, and motion graphics. Uses Logic Pro and Audacity for sound design and mixing/mastering. Fast learner, an efficient team player, focused hard-worker.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Paradise Bird - paradisebird.co

San Francisco, CA September 2017 - Present

Executive Producer

Helping businesses produce and distribute video content by telling a story about them or their customers. Managing a team of creative individuals to provide the best quality of storytelling on the market.

DmitryKotov.com - dmitrykotov.com

Los Angeles, CA July 2014 - September 2017

Video Producer

Produced video content by serving as a "Swiss army man" in a video production field to help teams raise awareness, help sales and support customers. Has grown a single man operation to a full-cycle production studio by engaging a vast network of vetted professionals around the globe.

Red Keds Creative Agency - redkeds.com

Video Producer

July 2014 - September 2017

Completed over 20 video projects, including commercial spots, product presentations, case studies, interviews, short films and educational content. Clients included: Infiniti, Kaspersky Lab, Central Partnership, L'Oréal, Unilever, IKEA.

EDUCATION

Moscow Engineering Physical Institute – Bachelor in Nuclear Physics, 2012 **Wordshop Courses of Film Production Management** - Film Producer, 2014